<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Ujjwal Chowdhury</title><link>https://u77w41.github.io/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Ujjwal Chowdhury</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://u77w41.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Certificates</title><link>https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/microsoft_dp100.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Certificates" />&lt;h2 id="microsoft-certified-azure-data-scientist-associate">Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Scientist Associate
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In this course, I gained subject matter expertise in applying data science and machine learning to implement and manage machine learning workloads on &lt;strong>Azure&lt;/strong>. I learned how to design and create suitable environments for data science projects, explore and analyze data, and train machine learning models. The course covered the implementation of pipelines and running jobs to prepare models for production. I also acquired skills in managing, deploying, and monitoring scalable machine learning solutions. Throughout the course, I developed a solid understanding and practical experience with &lt;strong>Azure Machine Learning&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>MLflow&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://learn.microsoft.com/api/credentials/share/en-us/u77w41/6DED7CA0675E173B?sharingId=2E0F4AA6DCCB6C73" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skills-learned">Skills Learned:
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;strong>MLFlow&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Docker&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Kubernetes&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Cloud Computing&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>AutoML&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>CI/CD Pipeline&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Data Bricks&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>PySpark&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>CosmosDB&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Blob Storage&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Data Visualization&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/microsoft_dp100.jpg"
width="1603"
height="882"
srcset="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/microsoft_dp100_hu7723930770422299536.jpg 480w, https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/microsoft_dp100_hu17710523455240318718.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="AzureDP100"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="181"
data-flex-basis="436px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="nism-series-xv-research-analyst">NISM-Series-XV: Research Analyst
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Completing the NISM Series XV Research Analyst examination equipped me with foundational knowledge of the &lt;strong>Indian Securities Markets&lt;/strong> and essential terminologies used in &lt;strong>Equity&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Debt Markets&lt;/strong>. I learned diverse &lt;strong>Research Methodologies&lt;/strong>, including top-down and bottom-up approaches, facilitating comprehensive analysis. Additionally, I honed skills in &lt;strong>Economic Analysis&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Industry and Company Evaluation&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Risk Management&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Valuation&lt;/strong> principles, and effective communication through research &lt;strong>Report Writing&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nism.ac.in/research-analyst-certification-examination/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skills-learned-1">Skills Learned:
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Micro and Macro-economic Analysis&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Fundamental Analysis&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Industry Analysis&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Company Analysis&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>KPI Analysis&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/NISM_Research_Analyst_Certificate.png"
width="2339"
height="1653"
srcset="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/NISM_Research_Analyst_Certificate_hu4113840077802801814.png 480w, https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/NISM_Research_Analyst_Certificate_hu17665954478509464731.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="NISM_XV_RA"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="141"
data-flex-basis="339px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="artificial-intelligence-ai-for-investments">Artificial Intelligence (AI) for Investments
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This program aims to prepare professionals in the finance industry and related fields for the transformative impact of machine learning (ML) and AI. It covers a comprehensive curriculum designed to equip participants with the knowledge and skills necessary to leverage AI and ML techniques in financial markets, trading, and asset management. From understanding &lt;strong>financial markets&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>risk-return analysis&lt;/strong> to advanced &lt;strong>time-series&lt;/strong> algorithms for risk management, the course provides practical insights and tools for improving investment decisions using AI-based models.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://onlinecourses.nptel.ac.in/noc23_mg63/preview" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skills-learned-2">Skills Learned:
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Portfolio Optimization&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>CAPM&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Algorithmic Trading&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>ARMA&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>ARIMA&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>ARCH&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>GARCH&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>3-Factor Fama-French Model&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Artificial_Intelligence_for_Investments.jpg"
width="3403"
height="2438"
srcset="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Artificial_Intelligence_for_Investments_hu16305315690298668702.jpg 480w, https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Artificial_Intelligence_for_Investments_hu16574523338847372645.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="AI_4_Investment"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="139"
data-flex-basis="334px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cloud-computing-and-distributed-systems">Cloud Computing and Distributed Systems
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In the course, I learned about &lt;strong>Cloud Computing&lt;/strong> fundamentals, including &lt;strong>virtualization techniques&lt;/strong> such as bare metal and &lt;strong>hosted hypervisor models&lt;/strong>, and the benefits and types of virtualization. Additionally, I gained insights into &lt;strong>network virtualization&lt;/strong> methods, software-defined networking, and inter-data center networking in geo-distributed cloud environments. Furthermore, the course covered topics like leader &lt;strong>election algorithms&lt;/strong>, distributed mutual exclusion, consensus mechanisms like &lt;strong>Paxos&lt;/strong>, recovery approaches in distributed systems, and the design and operation of key-value stores, along with discussions on &lt;strong>P2P&lt;/strong> systems and cloud applications like &lt;strong>MapReduce&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Spark&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Apache Kafka&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://onlinecourses.nptel.ac.in/noc23_cs27/preview" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skills-learned-3">Skills Learned:
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Virtual Machines&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Distributed Systems&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>NoSQL&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>MapReduce&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>PySpark&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Apache Kafka&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Cloud_Computing_and_Distributed_Systems.jpg"
width="3403"
height="2438"
srcset="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Cloud_Computing_and_Distributed_Systems_hu11607120609420380306.jpg 480w, https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Cloud_Computing_and_Distributed_Systems_hu16960638665054841025.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Colud_Computing"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="139"
data-flex-basis="334px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-base-management-system">Data Base Management System
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The course on Databases provides a comprehensive understanding of Structured Database Management Systems (&lt;strong>DBMS&lt;/strong>) and their significance in various applications, covering both commercial systems like Oracle and open-source solutions such as &lt;strong>MySQL&lt;/strong>. It delves into data structures, file organizations, SQL, data analysis, database design, and optimization, facilitating proficiency in relational data models, entity-relationship modeling, and query coding practices. Additionally, the course explores multi-tier client/server architectures, web-based database applications, and advanced topics including indexing, hashing, concurrency control, and recovery systems across its eight-week layout.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://onlinecourses.nptel.ac.in/noc22_cs91/preview" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skills-learned-4">Skills Learned:
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;strong>RDBMS&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>SQL&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Indexing&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Hashing&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Query Optimization&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>window function&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Data_Base_Management_System.jpg"
width="3403"
height="2438"
srcset="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Data_Base_Management_System_hu6375912690145608835.jpg 480w, https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Data_Base_Management_System_hu18126649891257840743.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="DBMS"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="139"
data-flex-basis="334px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deep-learning-for-computer-vision">Deep Learning for Computer Vision
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This course on Computer Vision begins with an overview of image and video analysis, emphasizing its applications in security, healthcare, entertainment, and mobility. It covers traditional computer vision topics and progresses to deep learning methods, assuming prior knowledge of machine learning. The curriculum includes a comprehensive exploration of visual features, matching techniques, deep learning fundamentals, CNN architectures, RNNs, attention models, generative models, and their applications in real-world scenarios over twelve weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://onlinecourses.nptel.ac.in/noc21_cs93/preview" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skills-learned-5">Skills Learned:
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Classical CV&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Multi-layer Perceptrons&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Backpropagation&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>CNN&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>RNN&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>AlexNet&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>VGG&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>ResNets&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>U-Net&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>VAE&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>GAN&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Zero-shot, One-shot, Few-shot Learning&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Deep_Learning_for_Computer_Vision.jpg"
width="3403"
height="2438"
srcset="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Deep_Learning_for_Computer_Vision_hu12837810719937426762.jpg 480w, https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Deep_Learning_for_Computer_Vision_hu9328172800314910983.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="DL4CV"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="139"
data-flex-basis="334px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-science-math-skills">Data Science Math Skills
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This data science course focuses on essential math skills crucial for success in data science, catering to learners with basic math proficiency who may not have studied algebra or pre-calculus. It systematically introduces core mathematical concepts without overwhelming complexity, ensuring learners grasp each idea and math symbol gradually. Upon completion, students will have mastered fundamental vocabulary, notation, concepts, and algebraic rules necessary for advanced data science studies. Topics covered include set theory, properties of real numbers, interval notation, summation, Cartesian plane math, functions and inverses, instantaneous rate of change, exponents, logarithms, and &lt;strong>probability theory&lt;/strong>, including &lt;strong>Bayes’ theorem&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/datasciencemathskills" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skills-learned-6">Skills Learned:
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Probability&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Bayes Theory&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Set Theory&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Linear Algebra&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Calculus&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Data_Science_Math_Skills.png"
width="2200"
height="1700"
srcset="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Data_Science_Math_Skills_hu15408464276987017070.png 480w, https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Data_Science_Math_Skills_hu14826797858330821582.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Data_Science_Math_Skills"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="129"
data-flex-basis="310px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reinforcement-learning">Reinforcement Learning
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This Reinforcement Learning course offers a comprehensive journey through foundational and advanced RL concepts. It begins with bandit algorithms for single-step decision-making and transitions into full RL with Markov Decision Processes (MDPs) and Bellman Optimality principles for sequential decision problems. Key techniques like Temporal Difference (TD) methods, eligibility traces, and function approximation are explored for value-based learning. Advanced methods, including Deep Q-Networks (DQN), policy gradients, and hierarchical RL, are covered to handle complex, real-world scenarios. The course concludes with Partially Observable MDPs (POMDPs), addressing decision-making in uncertain and incomplete environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://onlinecourses.nptel.ac.in/noc19_cs55/preview" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skills-learned-7">Skills Learned:
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Bandit algorithms&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>MDPs&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Bellman Optimality&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Eligibility Traces&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Hierarchical RL&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Policy Gradient for Full RL&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>POMDPs&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Reinforcement_Learning.jpg"
width="5318"
height="3810"
srcset="https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Reinforcement_Learning_hu17459930016908021703.jpg 480w, https://u77w41.github.io/certificates/Reinforcement_Learning_hu13577158123384746084.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Reinforcement_Learning"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="139"
data-flex-basis="334px"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Education</title><link>https://u77w41.github.io/education/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://u77w41.github.io/education/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://u77w41.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://u77w41.github.io/publications/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://u77w41.github.io/publications/publication.png" alt="Featured image of post Publications" />&lt;h1 id="investigate-how-market-behaves-toward-an-explanatory-multitasking-based-analytical-model-for-financial-investmentshttpsieeexploreieeeorgdocument10445412">&lt;a class="link" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10445412" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Investigate How Market Behaves: Toward an Explanatory Multitasking Based Analytical Model for Financial Investments&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>&lt;h2 id="authors">Authors:
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Sarmistha Das, Ujjwal Chowdhury, NS Lijin, Atulya Deep, Sriparna Saha, Alka Maurya&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="doi">DOI:
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/10445412" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3369033&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="publication-date">Publication date:
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>2024/2/26&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="journal">Journal:
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>IEEE Access&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="volume">Volume:
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>12&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pages">Pages:
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>30928-30940&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="publisher">Publisher:
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>IEEE&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="description">Description:
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In recent years, the intersection between financial market behavior and social media has emerged as a sought-after source of information, meeting the requirements of investors, institutions, regulators, researchers, and policymakers. Assessing sentiment and emotions aids in evaluating public psychology on particular stocks, assets, or the overall market, with shifts often aligning with market movements. Previously, machine learning, both traditional and deep learning methods, targeted discerning stock market sentiment and emotion without conducting studies to offer comprehensive explanations for these behavioral factors. In this study, we introduce a multitasking sequence-to-sequence model that integrates financial investment analysis with sentiment and emotion analysis from tweets upheld by an explanation mechanism. We also present the FinEMA dataset, featuring sentiment, emotion, and cause labels on financial stock market changes. Our study highlights how joint learning improves performance in discerning sentiment and emotion by utilizing interrelated features, enhancing task effectiveness. Our proposed model, the Emotion-Sentiment Attention Network (ESAN), achieved 89% accuracy in sentiment identification and 79% accuracy in emotion recognition, outperforming conventional machine learning methods. Furthermore, our findings indicate a positive outlook for the stock market in the latter half of 2023, which has intensified investor optimism, though some individuals still harbor uncertainties. Conclusively, our results suggest that regenerating existing computational tools can open up new research opportunities to address relevant novel tasks. The primary aim of this study is to elucidate the diverse dimensions of financial market behaviour and offer explanatory insights for the research community. The authors maintain impartiality towards specific stocks. It’s essential to note that stock market investments inherently carry market risks and potential losses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://u77w41.github.io/resume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://u77w41.github.io/resume/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;amp;id=1R667tZbNgTAn6vz5bEAdnt3C9fxyiWiw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Download Resume&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="areas-of-expertise">Areas of Expertise
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>NLP, Generative AI, Machine Learning Algorithms, Time Series Analysis, Algorithm Optimization, Statistical Analysis, Data Visualization, Model Development, Cross-functional Collaboration&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="skills">Skills
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Data Visualization: Microsoft Power BI, Excel, Tableau, Seaborn, Plotly, Matplotlib.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Machine Learning and Deep Learning: Feature Engineering, Model Development, Hyper-parameter Tuning, Neural Networks, Reinforcement Learning, Transfer Learning, Optimization Techniques, MLOps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tools/Frameworks: Python, R, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras, TFLite, MLFlow, PySpark, PostgreSQL, Azure, AWS, LangChain, streamlit, Docker, Pydantic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Natural Language Processing: Text Generation, Sentiment Analysis, Speech Recognition, Named Entity Recognition, Text Classification, LLM Prompt Engineering.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Computer Vision: Image Processing, Object Detection, Image Classification, Image Segmentation, Image Generation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Analysis and Mining: Data Mining, Web Scrapping, Statistical Analysis, Time Series Analysis, Anomaly Detection, Predictive Analytics, Survival Analysis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Soft Skills: Problem-Solving, Teamwork, Active Listening, Adaptability, Communication, Analytical Thinking.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="professional-experience">Professional Experience
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Research Executive (AI &amp;amp; NLP) (Feedsense AI Private Limited formerly Vista Intelligence) Kolkata, India (Jan 2023 - Present)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Utilized reinforcement learning models integrating financial data to predict market movements and develop optimized trading strategies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Led the NLP team, overseeing project developments and team operations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finetuned an RNN-Tranducer driven speech-to-text model to effectively capture Indian accents, decreasing the Word Error Rate from 56.8% to 23.4%.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developed a live audio transcription model for real-time news analysis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developed a trade signal generator model integrating live audio, textual news articles, OHLC data, and quantitative techniques. Achieved over 75% directional accuracy in generating Nifty F&amp;amp;O trading signals, enabling informed trading decisions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created an auto question generator program to generate questions based on applicant CVs, aiding the hiring team.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Utilized OpenAI API with Langchain to develop a large document summarizer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Employed a 4-bit quantized Mistral 7b LLM model for summarizing conference call conversations.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="research--publication">Research &amp;amp; Publication
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Investigate How Market Behaves: Toward an Explanatory Multitasking Based Analytical Model for Financial Investments (IEEE Access, March 2024) DOI: 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="courses--certifications">Courses &amp;amp; Certifications
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reinforcement Learning (Nov, 2024) - NPTEL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Microsoft DP-100: Azure Data Scientist Associate (June 2024) - Microsoft&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Artificial Intelligence (AI) for Investments (April 2023) - NPTEL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cloud Computing and Distributed Systems (March 2023) - NPTEL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NISM-Series-XV: Research Analyst (Feb. 2023) - National Institute of Securities Markets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Base Management System (Oct. 2022) - NPTEL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deep Learning for Computer Vision (Oct. 2022) - NPTEL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Science Math Skills (April 2020) - Duke University, Coursera&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="education">Education
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="msc-data-science-rkmveri-belur-west-bengal-india-aug-2021---june-2023">MSc Data Science RKMVERI Belur, West Bengal, India (Aug 2021 - June 2023)
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Relevant Courses: Probability &amp;amp; Stochastic Process, Data Structures &amp;amp; Algorithms, Statistics, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, NLP, Optimization Techniques, Linear Algebra, Time Series Analysis, Survival Analysis, Cloud Computing, Multivariate Statistical Analysis, Data Mining, DBMS&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bsc-mathematics-vidyasagar-university-medinipur-west-bengal-india-june-2017---oct-2020">BSc Mathematics Vidyasagar University Medinipur, West Bengal, India (June 2017 - Oct 2020)
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Relevant Courses: Set Theory, Calculus, Geometry &amp;amp; Differential Equation, Higher Algebra, Real Analysis, Differential Equations &amp;amp; Vector calculus, Group and Ring Theory, Theory of Equation, Graph Theory, PDE, ODE, DBMS, Operation Research, Numerical Methods&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="personal-projects">Personal Projects
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fin-Bot: Advanced Agent based Financial Chatbot&lt;/strong>
(Domain: NLP, LLM, Generative AI, Deep Learning, RAG)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Seamlessly integrated web search functionality ensuring comprehensive responses to queries.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implemented a custom vector database for efficient retrieval of financial news articles and concall transcripts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Employed LLM-equipped agent to direct user queries to relevant web or custom database, ensuring up-to-dated, comprehensive insights.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SALES FORECASTING AND ANOMALY DETECTION ON WALMART SALES DATASET&lt;/strong>
(Domain: Machine Learning, Time Series Analysis, Deep Learning)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Used Factor Analysis for feature extraction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Concepts of time series, machine learning, and deep learning are used to predict future sales.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Used unsupervised techniques to detect the anomalies.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Deep Bidirectional LSTM Network for Textual Sentiment Analysis&lt;/strong>
(Domain: Deep Learning, Sentiment Analysis, NLP, Web Scrapping)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Integrated Twitter API for real-time tweet scraping.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Utilized AsyncHTMLSession to scrape news articles from Google News.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leveraged Bi-LSTM architecture to process sequential data and extract meaningful features for sentiment classification.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>BRAIN TUMOUR CLASSIFICATION&lt;/strong>
(Domain: Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Optimization Techniques)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Used Transfer Learning and Fine-tuned several pre-trained models.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Explored different optimization algorithms such as Adam, RMSProp, SGD, GD, Adagrad etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Applied snapshot learning technique to construct an ensemble predictive model.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>STATISTICAL ANALYSIS OF DIET, EXERCISE AND FITNESS&lt;/strong>
(Domain: EDA, Data Visualization, Data Analysis, Statistical Inference)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Collected data using online surveys at different time frames.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Employed descriptive statistics to summarize the key characteristics of the dataset.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Used Power BI, Tableau, Excel, R, and Python for analysis and visualization.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://u77w41.github.io/archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://u77w41.github.io/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Links</title><link>https://u77w41.github.io/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://u77w41.github.io/links/</guid><description>&lt;p>To use this feature, add &lt;code>links&lt;/code> section to frontmatter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This page&amp;rsquo;s frontmatter:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">3
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">4
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">5
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">6
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">7
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">8
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">9
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="nt">links&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>- &lt;span class="nt">title&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="l">GitHub&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="nt">description&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="l">GitHub is the world&amp;#39;s largest software development platform.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="nt">website&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="l">https://github.com&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="nt">image&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="l">https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/logos_page/GitHub-Mark.png&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>- &lt;span class="nt">title&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="l">TypeScript&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="nt">description&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="l">TypeScript is a typed superset of JavaScript that compiles to plain JavaScript.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="nt">website&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="l">https://www.typescriptlang.org&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="nt">image&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w"> &lt;/span>&lt;span class="l">ts-logo-128.jpg&lt;/span>&lt;span class="w">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;p>&lt;code>image&lt;/code> field accepts both local and external images.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://u77w41.github.io/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://u77w41.github.io/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>